In this final lesson,
في هذا الدرس الأخير،
we will talk about what needs to be done when you've reached the end of the project.
سنتحدث عن ما يجب عمله عند نهاية المشروع.
This phase is important to smoothly close out
إنها مرحلة مهمه لإنهاء المشروع بسلاله
the project and also secure final payment from the client.
وضمان الدفعة الأخيرة من السداد من العميل.
Now let's look at what we will cover in this lesson.
الآن، دعونا نراجع ما سنقوم بالتحدث عنه في هذا الدرس.
First, we will talk about marking the deliverables as complete.
أولًا، سوف نناقش الانتهاء من جميع التسليمات.
Both the client and the developer are on the same page that the required job is done.
على العميل والمطور الاتفاق على أن المشروع المراد تنفيذه قد تم إنجازه.
Next, we'll talk about securing payments and sending invoices to clients wherever needed.
بعد ذلك، يتم مناقشة تأمين السداد وإرسال الفواتير الخاصة للعملاء وفق الحاجة.
We'll also talk about what to do in case we get a bad review on a freelancing platform.
سوف نناقش أيضًا سبل التعامل في حالة تلقي تقييم سيئ على منصة العمل الحر.
Lastly, we'll end with a quick recap of what we went through in this lesson.
في النهاية، سوف نراجع سريعًا ما تم تناوله في هذا الدرس.
Now let's look at what we'll be able to do at the end of this lesson.
لنقوم الآن بمراجعه ما يمكن القيام به في نهاية هذا الدرس.
First, we'll be able to effectively assess with
أولًا، سوف نتمكن من التقييم بفاعلية
the claim that all the deliverables are met.
الإيفاء بجميع التسليمات.
Then we'll be able to secure payments from the client and
يلي ذلك تأمين الدفع من قبل العميل
also be able to send invoices wherever needed.
وإرسال الفواتير وفق الحاجة.
Lastly, we'll also be able to manage situations where we get a bad review from
وأخيرًا، نتعامل مع أي موقف يتعلق بتقييم سيئ من
a client on a platform to reduce chances of defecting our future prospects.
العميل على المنصة لتفادى الوقوع في أخطاء أخرى مع العملاء المستقبليين.